[crowd cheering]
[host] Good evening. everyone!
We finally reached the highlight
of the Maharang Festival.
This event has been part
of our yearly tradition.
Who will emerge
as the Chili King and Queen of 2018?
[crowd cheers and applauds]
[host] Are you ready
for the Chili Challenge?
[host] Are you excited
to meet our contestants?
Let's all welcome them.
-[host cheers]
-[crowd cheers and applauds]
-Me!
-[Juancho] Bro!
-Get this guy!
-Not me!
-[host] Naga. make some noise!
-[man] Come on. come on!
[cheering and applauding]
[host] Okay. guys.
-[host] We only have four pairs so far.
-[Juancho] You should join!
We will get one more pair
from the audience.
-Me!
-[host] Who wants to join?
You want to join. right?
-[Juancho] Here. him!
-Me!
-This guy!
-[host] Any brave souls?
[host] That girl over there!
-Get me!
-[Juancho] This guy!
Do you have a partner?
Partner?
-Get my friend!
-I don't want to!
["Sako Ka Na Lang"
by Ched Valencia playing]
-[Juancho] Get my friend!
-[host] Any volunteer?
[host] Who wants to partner with her?
You! He's my partner!
-[host] There you go!
-Yes! Let's go!
Why me?
Come with me!
[host] Come up here on stage.
-[crowd cheering]
-[Zy] Hmm…
[host] Here we go!
The first pair to finish wins.
[gulps. pants] Water?
[Zy] It's so spicy. I can't.
[Juancho] Let me do it.
Can you still do it?
[host] These guys are almost done.
You can do it!
[host] Has anyone finished?
Go for it! Almost there!
[shouts]
[both shout]
[crowd cheering]
[host] We have a winner!
Please give it up
for your 2018 Chili King and Queen!
[bowl thuds]
Try my kinalas.
It's for my future restaurant.
It's my first time to try this.
Is it good?
How is it?
Thank you. [chuckles]
I told you it's good.
-[both laugh]
-[Zy] This is so good.
Why don't you bring this to Manila?
[chuckles] Careful!
[Juancho] Which one? The kinalas or me?
[Zy] Hmm…
I guess both.
So. come fly with me to Manila?
[bright music playing]
[music fades]
[distant chattering]
Miss Anita!
-Juancho.
-Wow! You look blooming today.
What brings you here?
My courage and my confidence
in Casa Rosa. ma'am.
My gosh! I've already spoken
with Aiah. and I'm sorry.
but my friends don't think
Casa Rosa will click in Manila.
Ma'am. you're wasting a very good
investment opportunity here.
Oh my gosh! You're stressing me out!
-My cortisol level is rising!
-Oh…
-Calm down.
-Put my bags inside the van now.
I mean. my God!
[Anita exhales sharply]
Miss Anita!
[upbeat music playing]
You know what?
We have a Chef's Special Night tonight.
Seven p.m.
And the best table
is reserved just for you.
For me?
Just for me?
-Stop!
-[assistant] Stop. Stop.
-[man] Yes. ma'am.
-Yes!
[Juancho] Bro. let's start with the prep!
Are the ingredients ready?
[Epi on phone] Yes. we're ready.
Good! Good!
Bro. just like any other night.
tell everyone that we have
no room for mistakes.
I'll take care of it.
Okay. okay.
[distant explosion]
[woman screams]
-[woman] It's burning!
-[Epi] What happened?
A tricycle broke down.
-[chuckles]
-[woman] Hello!
-[woman] Hello? Come on!
-[man] What happened here?
[Epi] Hello. bro?
Bro. are you still there?
[rousing music playing]
[Juancho] Bro. please prepare
one seat in the open kitchen.
I'm just gonna tempt someone.
Okay. copy.
[engine revving]
Yes. Agi. it's okay. I'm right here.
-[yelps]
-[brakes screech]
Sir. what the hell?
You almost ran me over!
You know? Just give me my food.
Can I just have it?
[rousing music playing]
[Juancho] I'm sorry.
Hey!
Zy. how have you been?
What are you doing here?
I'm… I'm just waiting… for… food delivery.
Here? In Naga?
Naga.
When did you arrive?
Are you here to visit your family?
No. [stammers] I'm just here for work.
-For work.
-Yeah.
Since when?
Just this morning.
Okay.
Until when are you here?
Just for a while.
Like… ten days
and then I'm going back to New York.
[Zy clears throat]
Awkward. isn't it?
What?
It's awkward.
[snorts]
Zy. let's be honest.
We didn't have a good break-up.
so now. it's awkward.
[scoffs]
I knew it! You're still mad!
Oh my God!
You're still mad.
Of course. Zy!
You made a fool out of me!
You were selfish. And… a bitch!
[scoffs]
Well… I had to be one.
just so that I could survive
being in a relationship
with a… boy like you.
Wow.
So. you really have no plans to apologize?
Why?
Would my apology still matter now?
[upbeat music playing]
[delivery rider clears throat]
Delivery. ma'am.
Is that for me?
Thank you.
-[delivery rider] Thank you.
-Thank you.
-[snorts]
-It's nice seeing you again. I have to go.
Is that what you're eating?
Fast food?
Why don't you eat at the restaurant?
Why? You don't want to?
Or you can't?
No. of course not. I'm just really hungry.
Perfect! Let me make
Bicol Express for you.
Spicy. sweet. oily.
-Just how you like it.
-[stomach growls]
See?
[laughs heartily]
I heard that! Let's go!
Or maybe you don't want to come with me
-because you're still not over me.
-Can you stop? My God!
[motorcycle engine humming]
[Zy clears throat]
Come in.
-[enchanting music playing]
-[indistinct chattering]
[Zy] Wow!
It looks different.
Yup. We renovated and updated our menu.
I recreated Grandma Rosa's dishes.
Enjoy your food. sir.
I put up an open kitchen inside.
We also have Chef's Special Nights
during weekends.
Your timing is perfect.
-[woman 1] Hi. Chef Juancho.
-[Juancho] Hello.
-[Juancho] Hi. hi.
-[vlogger] Please say "hi" to our vlog.
-[Juancho] Hi. vlog!
-[women] Hi!
[Juancho] Chef Juancho from Casa Rosa.
[vloggers] Thank you. Chef.
[Lala] Good day! Welcome to Casa Rosa!
-La. two tables.
-Yes?
-One for her and one for our investor.
-Sure.
[Lala] I'll take care of that. boss.
-[Jon] This one right here.
-Here it is.
-this is Rosa Fresca.
-the open kitchen!
[Jon] All the ingredients
are freshly picked
-Hold on.
-from our farm outside.
We will serve this in a bit.
[woman] Thank you.
This is Jon. He's training
to be the head chef
for our new branch in Manila.
-You're so beautiful. ma'am.
-[chuckles]
-[Epi] Hurry up.
-[chuckles] Thank you.
Okay? Bro.
Yes. bro?
Why?
-[Epi] Menu.
-Menu.
Papa Jun. Zy is here.
-Thank you.
-Epi. double time.
-[Epi] Yes.
There are so many customers.
Papa Jun had a stroke
more than a year ago.
I took over the restaurant since then.
Let me know if there's
anything else you want.
I'll send someone over to assist you.
Hmm?
You still have that?
Yup.
[Juancho] I'm not ready to let go…
of the bird.
-[Lala] Sir?
-Excuse me.
-Hold this for me. La.
-Okay.
[Juancho] Don't go.
[indistinct chattering]
[Juancho] Jon. how are we doing?
[Jon] Everything's good. boss.
-Psst! Hey. bro.
-[Juancho] Yes?
What is Zy doing here?
Why are you together?
[Juancho] She's in for a treat.
I'll make her join our Chili Challenge.
[Epi] Stop fooling around.
Waiter.
Where's the restroom?
I'll take care of Zy's order.
so you can focus on the investor.
No. I'm already on it.
I'll do it. You might poison her.
-I won't poison her.
-Really?
I'll just make her regret.
[Jon] Who is she anyway?
What do you mean?
Are you planning to get back with her?
Who are you getting back with?
I'm not getting back with her.
I will get back at her.
[clicks tongue] I'll ask her then.
-Hey!
-Wait!
That's Zy.
His Zy.
As in Zy?
[mischievous music playing]
Your psycho ex-girlfriend?
Yes.
Oh no! You're dead.
Not you. boss.
I meant Zy.
It's showtime!
[seductive music playing]
[sizzling]
[gas ignition clicks]
[flame ignites]
[sizzling]
[seductive music continues]
[simmering]
[mouthing] I'm hungry.
[mouthing] Just a sec.
[music stops]
[fork clinks on plate]
[Juancho] Your apology won't matter now
because I've already forgiven you.
-[coughs]
-[fork clinks on plate]
-[spoon clinks on plate]
What?
Just to answer your question earlier.
if your apology would still matter now?
Oh.
You really mean that?
[chuckles] Of course!
I mean. look at us now.
We both reached our dreams.
You in New York.
me with my restaurant.
Right.
[chuckles] Right.
Look at you.
You're not a boy anymore.
You've matured.
I'm proud of you.
So. your work. How's everything?
Are you covering an event?
Or an article to write?
-Yeah--
-Wait.
Do you still write?
Yeah.
Articles.
About what?
About Bicolano food.
Perfect!
Is there anything you need to know?
You can ask me.
No. it's okay.
I'm in contact with a tourism officer.
He said he'll help me.
Okay.
How's the food?
It's good!
No wonder you have a lot of customers.
[chortles]
The Bicol Express…
Did you change it?
Because the flavors are…
It's too strong.
Like it's showing off.
Maybe it's just me.
[chuckles] Yeah.
It's just you.
That's our best-seller.
Excuse me.
Enjoy your food.
[Juancho] Good evening. Miss Anita.
Welcome to Casa Rosa.
-[Juancho] Let's go.
-[Anita] Okay.
[Juancho] Tonight.
you will not just taste the heat.
you will experience it.
This is your special seat.
Thank you. Wow.
Really up front and center.
To see where the magic happens.
All right. everyone!
Excuse me.
As you all know.
Bicol is known for its chili.
The closer to the volcano.
the spicier the chili is.
That's one of the things
we honor here at Casa Rosa.
And part of our Chef's Special Night
is the Chili Challenge.
[customers cheering]
And tonight is a special night because
the Maharang Fest
2018 Chili Queen is here.
Zy Angeles!
-[rousing music playing]
-[customers cheering]
[chanting] Chili Queen! Chili Queen!
And she will defend her title tonight.
[chanting] Chili Queen!
-I can't.
-You can.
-I can't do it.
-Of course. you can.
-You can do it.
-[crowd] Chili Queen!
-[Lala] We believe in you.
-[Zy] I can't. La.
[chanting] Chili Queen! Chili Queen!
[Zy] Okay. fine.
I will only join if you join.
Right?
-Chili King 2018.
-[Lala] Oh. yeah!
-Right!
-That's correct!
[chanting] Chili King! Chili King!
Chili King!
[Jon] For the Chili Challenge.
each pair will go through
three spicy rounds.
Round one.
-The irresistibly
-Hey! Don't stop!
hot spicy Laing.
[gasping] So spicy!
[Jon] Round two.
The dangerous
and delectable Bicol Express.
Let's go. Zy!
Okay.
[exhales sharply]
[rousing music continues]
[Zy] Okay.
Okay. game!
Fuck.
[Zy] Oh my God! It's so hot!
[panting] Fuck. fuck.
[Jon] For the final round.
the enticing yet deadly Bicol Chili.
-[muffled panting]
-[muffled groans]
-[muffled groaning]
[gasps]
[exclaims]
[customers cheering]
[cheering continues]
[music fades out]
[gulps]
[Zy exhales sharply] It still burns!
This sugar cube should help.
[sensual music playing]
[smooch]
[Zy moans]
[Zy] Ouch.
[sensual rock music playing]
I'm getting married.
[muffled dialogue]
[Epi] So you'll see her again?
[Jon] I thought she's getting married.
Zy is getting married?
What a bunch of crap!
Then why did she come with you?
That's not what a decent lady does!
Even if Tin and I are apart
and her exes are also in Manila.
one is even her neighbor.
she never interacts with them.
She's so loyal to me.
That's why I want to marry her.
That's a decent girlfriend.
And you're saying Zy is engaged?
She shouldn't be flirting with her ex!
What the hell?
She's already fooled you once.
Wasn't that enough?
Bro. she wronged you.
-[heavy chopping]
-[Epi] Okay?
[pensive music playing]
[computer keyboard clicks]
[footsteps descending]
[Zy] Coffee? Do we have coffee?
Ba.
Laya's menu.
-Careful.
-I'm rushing.
Our first baby.
I have to go. Ba. Sorry.
-I'll check it later!
-Ba!
[Juancho] Ma'am. sir. free taste?
[Juancho] Kinalas nachos.
We have a promo today.
-Wanna try?
-[Zy] Yeah.
Okay!
Yes. I'm free. I can interview her.
Zy!
[whispers] I have to go. Cover for me.
[heavy chopping]
[knife thumps]
She didn't just wrong me.
[man] Let me know if there's
anything else you want to sell.
I'm sorry Laya didn't work out.
[Juancho] We said we'd reach
our dreams together.
but she only thought of herself.
[Zy] They accepted my application
for a part-time job.
-[woman on video call] Really?
-[Zy] Yeah!
[Zy] Yeah. and I'm really so grateful!
You have no idea.
I feel like everything
is really falling into place.
-[woman on video call] That's great.
-[chair scrapes]
Yeah. Sorry. I'll just move.
[woman] Do you already have
your plane ticket?
[Zy] Yeah. I--
[woman] Please check
all the requirements that I sent you.
Yes. I have everything here. ma'am.
I have it with me.
[gloomy music playing]
[Juancho] She turned
her back on our dreams.
She made new plans without me.
Will you marry me?
Stop.
Stop it. Juancho.
[Juancho] Ba. please.
I'm sorry.
[inhales sharply]
Please. I can't.
[Juancho] It was so easy
for her to drop me
just because she reached her dreams.
[line ringing]
Zy?
Zy. why aren't you picking up?
[Zy] Juancho. please stop.
Let's talk! Let's fix this. okay?
[thunder roaring]
Let's talk about it. please?
I'm begging you.
I'll apply for a visa again.
I'll follow you there!
I met someone new in New York.
What?
[line disconnects]
Bro?
-[line ringing]
-Bro.
[line ringing]
-[busy tone]
-Juancho!
Juancho. let's go!
-Let's go back to Bicol.
-[line ringing]
[line ringing]
-Juancho!
-[busy tone]
Let's go home. dammit! Look at yourself!
Wait!
Let's go!
Fuck! [cries]
-What?
-Wait!
[line ringing. busy tone]
[sobbing] Zy.
[line ringing]
[Jun] Stop this!
-[line ringing]
-Dammit.
-[smacks]
-[Jun] Stop this!
[morose music playing]
[sobbing]
Zy didn't just wrong me.
She insulted me. neglected me.
humiliated me. abandoned me.
and cheated on me.
That's right. boss!
So. let her feel your wrath.
[Jon] She's evil.
She doesn't deserve to be happy.
Screw her!
[pensive music playing]
[exhales deeply]
[phone vibrating]
-Hi. babe.
-[Matt on phone] Hi. babe.
How are you?
How's Bicol?
Good.
It's hot. though.
How was your research? Have you started?
No. not yet. We'll start tomorrow.
-I'll do some immersion with the suanoys.
-Mm-hmm.
-They know the heirloom recipes.
-That's good.
Good luck!
You seem tired. Jetlag?
Or did you see people
that you didn't want to see?
Well…
I saw Juancho.
Juancho.
Well. what can you expect?
You're in Bicol. He's from there.
Why?
How bad was it?
He was…
civil.
I can go there for you
if you need me there.
How?
You're too busy. babe.
Yeah. Guilty.
Well. anyway. good luck with your article.
Your first byline should be impressive.
so David could give you
more writing assignments.
Yeah.
I will.
I mean.
that's what I'm here for.
For work.
Anyway. babe. I have to start my day
and get ready for work.
I'll see you soon.
Get some sleep.
-I love you.
-I love you. too.
-Bye.
[phone thuds]
[exhales deeply]
[paper rustles]
[Juancho] You're visiting Grandma Maring?
She's my Grandma Rosa's friend.
Yes. sir. Ms. Zy asked me
to look for suanoys
for her research.
Hi. Zy!
-Good morning!
-Ms. Zy Angeles?
-I'm Ronnie. your tourism officer.
-Yes?
Do you want to interview
Chef Juancho first?
He's off the list.
Zy.
[playful music playing]
[Juancho] You left this.
Thank you.
For this or for last night?
[whispers] That shouldn't have happened.
And it meant nothing.
so there's no point in us talking.
I don't wanna see you anymore.
[Ronnie] We'll go ahead. sir.
[line ringing]
[phone ringing]
Oh.
Hello. Juancho? What is it?
[Juancho] Hello. Grandma Maring.
I need a favor.
[Maring] The crazy girl?
What will I do with her?
Can I interview you?
-Oh no! You can't!
-I just have questions about your laing.
I will poison her!
If you're gonna interview me in Tagalog.
just go home.
-This will be quick.
-Wait!
[Zy] Oh my God!
I'm dead!
I'm so--
You still have rice on your face.
[Vilma] I told you to leave your husband.
He's useless!
Grandma V! How have you been?
My baby. How are you?
Grandma. prepare the coconuts.
She's on her way to you.
[Vilma] The crazy girl?
Maring already spilled the tea.
[groaning]
She'll grate these coconuts to death!
-Grandma V. my lovey!
-My baby.
[Juancho] Zy! Is that you?
Is this your sideline?
[Vilma] Do it properly.
[Juancho] This is how you do it.
[machine whirring]
[Vilma] I'm ready. Let's go!
-[Juancho] Alright!
-Grandma. what about our interview?
Pretend you have
a headache until tomorrow.
-[Vilma] Like this.
-I'll take care of her research.
-Ouch! I have a headache!
-[Vilma] Please look after the store.
-[Juancho] Grandma. let's go! Zy!
-[Vilma] Let's go!
Grandma Zon!
The tea that you gave me the other day…
Did you drink all of it?
It cured my hangover!
[Juancho] Grandma. let's do the ritual.
[Vilma] We're here!
[Zon] The others told me that she's crazy.
Well. let's see if she stands
a chance against us.
[Zon] Cooking cassava pudding is sacred.
You need to be free of sins.
[chanting] Have mercy! Have mercy!
Say it to Juancho.
Have mercy!
-[Vilma] Make it more affectionate.
-Have mercy!
-[Vilma] With feelings.
[Zy] Please?
Forgive me?
Please?
Okay?
[playful music continues]
-[paddle boat shaking]
-[water sloshing]
[Zy] Oh my God!
[Zy screaming]
-[Zy] Oh my God!
-[children laugh]
[Zy] Juancho. oh my goodness! Oh my God!
-[Zy] What the hell?
-[Juancho] What?
-[Zy] Juancho! Seriously!
-[Juancho] You're too serious!
-[Zy] Juancho! Please.
-[Juancho] More?
Juancho! Please.
Stop it! I'm serious!
Are you okay?
[Zy] Do you really have to catch
the crablets yourself?
[Juancho] Not really.
You can catch them for me. Want to try?
[Zy] Hmm… No. thanks.
See that?
That's the trap
where we also put the food.
Is that really necessary?
Of course! I'll be soaked with sweat.
You see this?
The crablets will bite the food
until they are trapped.
[uplifting music playing]
[water sloshing]
[quirky sting]
[quirky music playing]
Zy. I'm not the food.
What's there to bite? You're so thin!
Excuse me. You bit this before.
Not just bite.
Consumed!
Oh my God. You're so annoying.
Consumed.
-[Zy] I'll do it.
-No. I'll do it.
[Zy] Stop blabbering. Give it to me!
-Give me.
-[Juancho] Careful!
-Do you even know how to do it?
-[grunts]
[screaming] Oh my God!
-We might fall!
-Oh my God!
[Zy] Oh my God!
-[Juancho] Breathe.
-[gasping heavily]
-Breathe.
-[panting]
I'm so scared.
-[tender music playing]
-[breathes shakily]
[Juancho] Come in.
I'll teach you how to make tinuktok.
How's your article?
[Zy] Uhm…
I still need to do more research.
Weren't the grandmas helpful?
Yeah. It was… helpful.
I see the value in traditional cooking.
Yeah. That's why I want to use that
for the new dish
in my Manila branch.
It's new and yet.
the flavor of Bicol is still there.
Why don't you write about me?
About Casa Rosa?
That's interesting.
[water sploshes]
Well. I do need to submit
my piece tomorrow.
So…
you'll write about me?
My food?
Yeah. I can write about Casa Rosa.
I'll interview you.
[footsteps approaching]
-I'd like that.
-[door clicks shut]
[Aiah] Babi?
-Babi. you're here! [screams joyfully]
-I'm here!
[Aiah] Put me down.
I've missed you.
[Aiah] Missed you too.
If you looked at my messages.
-you'd know I was here.
-Hey. relax.
[Juancho] You smell so good!
And you look prettier after a shower!
Stop it.
-Oh. Babi.
-Hi. Hello.
[Aiah] My God. I'm so sorry.
-[Juancho] Zy. this is Babi.
-[Aiah] Hi.
My partner. Babi. this is Zy.
-Old friend.
-[Aiah] Hmm.
[Aiah] Okay. Hi.
Hi.
Babi. Zy is a writer in New York.
She's writing about Bicolano food.
and I'm helping her.
She'll also feature Casa Rosa.
Oh. nice! Okay.
Actually.
I was just going to… leave you guys.
We could… We could just resume.
I guess. tomorrow?
No. It's okay.
-[Aiah] You can stay.
-It's so nice meeting you.
-Okay. Bye.
-[Zy] Bye.
[Aiah] Bye.
I think she felt awkward.
You should've clarified
that I'm just your business partner.
She got jealous. right?
Oh my God.
Honestly. I don't care.
Anyway. Miss Anita said no as an investor.
So. let's proceed
with the investors' dinner.
And I'm thinking. we should do it here.
Miss Anita has a point.
We should make it a bar and restaurant.
Do you think Papa Jun will approve?
If Papa Jun approves.
then we can do
the cocktail tasting tomorrow.
[pensive music playing]
[line ringing]
[Juancho on phone]
It's a shame you left early.
You didn't get
to try the crablets we caught.
[Zy on phone] How did you cook it?
[Juancho] Well. I made it into a bar chow.
Basically. tinuktok bites.
We need to expand our menu
to cater to our future Manila branch.
[Zy] So. wait.
you're gonna change Casa Rosa in Manila?
[Juancho] Not entirely.
We just need to introduce dishes
that could appeal to the Manila market
while using Bicolano elements.
That's why the investors' dinner
is crucial for us to test this out.
[Zy] I see.
That's interesting.
I'm curious how
the investors would receive
your concept about fusion.
I hope they would appreciate
how you keep up
with the times
without sacrificing your roots.
[Juancho] I know.
Actually. why don't you come
to the cocktail tasting tomorrow?
We will make signature drinks
using Bicolano ingredients.
It might help with the new direction
of your article.
[Zy] Sure. I can join.
Is it okay if I invite Lei?
[Juancho] Of course!
Invite your brother.
[Zy] Okay. I'll see you.
Thanks for today. Juancho.
[Juancho] No worries. Bye.
[call ends]
[pensive music continues]
[sighs]
Thank you very much.
[woman] Thank you also.
[Jon] Yes!
Early closing. so we can go drinking!
[Aiah cheering. clapping]
Yes. I'm so ready!
Why close early? Not good for profit.
[Lala] As long as we get paid the same.
there's no problem.
-[Juancho] Thank you for coming. ma'am.
-[woman] Thank you also.
-[Juancho] Jon.
-[Jon] Boss.
[Aiah] Hey! Perfect!
So glad you could join us. Zy.
-[Lei] Zy?
-I hope you're getting…
[Lei] Finally. you decided to show up!
You're so workaholic!
Hmm?
Lei.
[both chuckle]
-Hi.
-Sis. where is Matt?
[Lei] Why isn't he with you?
He's in New York.
We're okay. Don't worry.
Look. I'm getting married.
-Sis! Oh my gosh!
-[giggling]
I thought you're back together
with Juancho.
-Lei.
-Oh.
No offense. Juancho.
But for now. we're celebrating!
Sis. you're getting married!
We should celebrate!
Another reason to drink. right?
-Come on. I say let's go!
-Let's go!
We'll just start preparing.
[upbeat music playing]
[Jon] This is a little strong.
What's a good name?
[Epi] Cassava drink.
Crushed and beaten to goodness.
-[Lei] That's savage!
-[Lala] That's it.
That's it.
"Cas-savage".
-Oh!
-[chuckles]
-[Juancho] "Cas-savage".
-[laughter]
[Jon] Okay. next drink.
What should we call this one?
The taste of a martyr.
-[Lei] That's me!
-[laughs]
[Epi] He's a martyr too!
-Excuse me.
-[Juancho] Me?
My sister's a martyr. too!
Let's call it "Apple Martyr-ni".
-Nice!
-[chuckles]
[Jon] Okay. next drink.
-[Juancho] Now. what?
-[Aiah] Oh my God.
This tastes like pure alcohol.
It's like gas.
Oh my God!
-"Unleaded".
-[Juancho] What?
-Any objections?
-[laughter]
[Aiah] Good. right?
-[indistinct chatter]
Okay. everybody.
-[Aiah] Let's make a toast.
-[Lei shrieks]
-Cheers to Zy's wedding!
-[Epi] Cheers to that!
-[Lei] Cheers!
-[Epi] Cheers!
-[Lala] Cheers!
-[indistinct chatter]
A managing editor and a beautiful writer.
What a perfect match!
-[Lei] Yes! My ship has sailed!
-[glasses clink]
-[phone vibrating]
-[Lei] Your phone's vibrating.
Someone's calling you.
-[Zy] I'll get it later.
-[Lei] It's Matt.
-[Zy] It's okay.
-[Lei] Sis.
-I'll answer it.
-Lei.
-[Aiah] Cheers!
-Let me answer it.
[squeals]
-Hi. Matt!
-[Matt on phone] Lei!
-How are you?
-[Lei] This is your B.I.L.
Brother-in-law!
We're celebrating your engagement.
Look.
-[Lei] Say hi. everyone.
-[Matt] Wow!
-[Lala] Hello.
-[Lei] He said hi!
-[Matt] Looks like a great party.
-[Lala] Hello!
Hi. everyone! I wish I was there.
Can I talk to your sister?
Yeah. okay.
[Lei] I ran out of English.
-[Matt] Babe. enjoy your night.
-[Zy] Okay. babe.
Don't drink too much.
You have work tomorrow.
I won't get drunk. I promise.
-I love you.
-[Zy] Okay. I love you too.
[Zy] I'll talk to you later.
Okay. Bye.
Bye.
[glass thuds]
Are you done?
You're done.
Next drink.
-My favorite.
-[Epi] Okay. okay.
Blue pea passion fruit.
[Lei] This is good!
-It's sweet!
-Right?
[Lei] This is for you. sis.
You and Matt!
Lei. you're right.
It's good. but it's deadly.
It will sneak up on you.
Like a traitor.
[Aiah sighs heavily]
[Juancho] Zy. try it.
I'm sure you'll like that.
[Aiah sighs]
Babi. next drink. Jon. bring it here.
No. Babi. We're not yet done.
Zy hasn't tried it yet. Zy. try it.
Just enjoy it.
At first. it will delight you.
and then. boom!
There's a twist.
It turns sour. then you're all alone.
You're all alone because you're drunk!
Zy. don't look so guilty.
[Epi] Next drink.
Let's have some coffee.
-[Epi] Someone's already drunk.
-[Aiah] Right. right.
Who's drunk. bro?
I'm not drunk.
We're just brainstorming here.
Has anyone thought of a name yet?
Nothing?
Okay. what if… Uhm…
"I Met Someone New In New York".
-[Juancho laughing]
-[Epi] He's drunk.
[Juancho] Zy. what do you think?
-[Juancho] Huh?
-[Epi] That's enough.
-What do you think? No? [clicks tongue]
-Come on now.
[Juancho] Or if you want.
we can take Lei's suggestion.
He said you're like that drink.
Let's call it "Zy".
You're a traitor. right?
-[Lei] That's not what I said. Juancho.
-[bangs table]
-[Jun] That's enough!
-That's what you said.
-[Jun] Let's pack up!
-[Aiah] Let's go home.
-[Epi] You're drunk.
-[Aiah] Right. let's go.
Hey. Zy! No comment?
That's enough.
What?
I'll go ahead.
-You're leaving again!
-Juancho. please stop. That's enough.
That's right!
That's what you said to me that night.
On the phone. remember?
"Juancho. please stop."
The nerve to say "please"!
Bro.
-Good times. Good times.
-[Epi] Good times. bro.
[Juancho] Next drink!
Let's call it
"Matt".
[Epi mumbles]
[tense music playing]
Matt.
-[Jun] Juancho.
-[Epi] That's enough.
He was next after me. right?
Bro. that's enough.
-[Epi] That's enough.
-The nerve to talk to him in front of me!
-You're unbelievable.
-Juancho.
I never cheated on you.
Not with Matt.
-Not with anyone.
-Bullshit!
[morose music playing]
[sniffles]
I lied.
To make you stop begging.
I'll go ahead.
-[Aiah] Zy. I'm sorry.
-It's okay.
Thank you.
[Aiah] I'm so sorry.
[Zy] Mm-hmm.
-[morose music continues]
-[indistinct chatter]
[engine revving]
[morose music continues]
[laughter echoing]
[Zy] Ba. look at our signage for Laya.
Here. Have a drink first.
[Zy] Help me finish this.
Just follow one stroke.
One stroke. okay?
[Juancho] Like this?
[Zy] Ba. just one stroke.
-[Juancho] That's what I'm doing.
-[Zy] Just one stroke.
[Zy] Hey!
-You want to play around?
-[Juancho] I'm working!
-Here!
-Huh?
-Mm…
-Ba!
[laughing]
[Zy] Ba!
[poignant music playing]
[Juancho] Ba. I'm still short on money.
[Zy] Didn't I tell you?
I found a new investor!
Who?
It's me!
[Zy] I don't mind postponing
my scholarship in New York.
I'll invest in you. Ba.
I'll invest in us.
I know it will be worth it.
[Zy] No matter what happens.
I will always be here.
Give me a smile. Ba.
-Smile!
-Thank you.
-[line ringing]
-I love you lots.
[landlord] Zy. I got a lot of complaints
from the other stalls.
They said Juancho doesn't clean up.
[Zy] I'm so sorry.
I'll take care of it.
[landlord] Make sure
this won't happen again.
[Zy] Why can't you put
the clothes inside the basket?
-[Zy] Why can't you do that?
-[Juancho] I'm doing it.
[Juancho] What else do you want?
-[Juancho] Give it to me!
-I'll do it!
-Give it to me!
-I do everything here anyway!
-I said I'll do it!
-I said give it to me!
You couldn't even do this simple thing?!
You're like a child!
Where are you going?
Away from you!
[door opens. then slams shut]
[Juancho on phone] Zy!
Why aren't you picking up?
Juancho.
Please. stop.
That's enough.
Let's talk! Let's fix this. okay?
Please. I'm begging you.
Let's talk about this. Ba.
I'll apply for a visa again.
I'll follow you there!
I promised. didn't I?
I met someone new in New York.
What?
[phone vibrating]
-[Zy sobbing]
-[phone continues vibrating]
Zy! Zy. we need to talk.
Juancho. I'm not in the mood. Please.
Is it--
Is it true? What you said earlier?
That you didn't cheat on me?
-[elevator dings]
-Let's talk some other day.
Some other day? Zy. let's talk now!
If there was no one else.
why did you leave me? Tell me the truth!
-Zy. let's talk--
-Just leave. Juancho.
I don't want to talk!
[Juancho] No! We have to talk!
I told you earlier
that I wanted you to stop.
-Zy. I'm part of--
-Now. can you just stop?
Zy. I'm part of that relationship.
I deserve to know the truth!
What's the point
of talking about this now?
What's the point?
The point is you hurt me.
You fooled me and you're still fooling me!
For two years. you made me believe
that there was someone else.
Every night for two years.
I asked myself why.
Why did you replace me so fast?
Why did you just
throw me away like I'm trash?
Fuck! What does he have that I don't?
Is he more handsome?
Richer? Better?
Is he fucking better in bed?
Fuck.
I doubted myself for two years!
I was cursing you every day.
I wanted to hurt you.
I wanted to ruin your life.
And now.
you want me to believe
that all of it was a lie?
So. what's the truth? Huh?
Because I don't even know why I'm hurting!
[morose music playing]
I'm sorry. Juancho.
I'm sorry I made you feel that way.
Stop saying sorry.
Your apology is useless
if you won't tell the truth.
What's the truth? Why did you leave me?
After everything that I've done for you?
I even followed you in Manila.
-That was your decision!
-even though it was hard!
I put up a restaurant for you
so I could keep up--
-I was just helping you!
-Helping me?
Fuck! You call that helping?
When I was failing. you abandoned me!
[exhales shakily]
-[water running]
-[sobbing]
Stop crying.
Zy. I just want to know the truth.
Zy. tell me.
Zy. what's so hard about
telling the truth?
Talk to me!
Tell me!
What's the truth?
-Tell me the truth!
-I got tired!
I got tired of carrying you!
I didn't want to drown with you.
Juancho. believe me I tried.
God knows I tried my best to help you.
But I could only do so much.
I didn't know how else to help you.
Because you didn't want to man up
and help yourself.
Yes. you did everything for me.
but I was willing to give up
everything for you too. Juancho!
I wasn't just your girlfriend.
I had to act like your mother.
I had to be the adult one
in the relationship
because you were acting like a child.
I endured that.
I endured that because we promised
that we were going
to build a life together.
But it was so hard to carry both of us.
I was the only one fighting.
I was starting to drown. too.
I was spent.
[morose music playing]
[sobs]
God. I hated loving you so much.
And I needed you to man up.
I needed my boyfriend.
I needed my partner back.
But that didn't happen.
You wanted to marry me.
but we were both miserable.
If you hated me. I hated myself. too.
If you were hurt. I was hurting. too.
You wanted to punish me.
I was punishing myself every day.
Why did I give up on the person I love?
Why did I let go?
Someone had to do it.
Someone had to end it.
And I know you couldn't do it.
You're right.
There are two of us in the relationship.
And the two of us will drown
together if no one ends it.
I'm sorry. Juancho.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I hurt you.
[Juancho exhales sharply]
-[door clicks open]
-[Zy sighs]
[door clicks shut]
[morose music continues]
[liquid pouring]
[Epi] She didn't leave you
because she doesn't love you.
She was just hurt. too.
[bottle clinks]
She suffered so much in your relationship.
[morose music playing]
Boss. what if
she told you the truth then?
Maybe you'd still be together now.
I don't think so.
They're done.
It is what it is.
But at least…
you two were able to talk it out.
Right?
And she apologized to you.
What about you. boss?
Have you apologized?
[morose music continues]
-[music fades]
-[Jon sighs]
Thank you so much for all your help.
Just message me if you need anything else.
Thank you.
-[car door clicks shut]
-[engine revving]
Zy.
I'm sorry.
[gentle music playing]
Do you need anything else
for your research?
Maybe I can help.
We're finalizing the details
for the investors' dinner.
Will that help you finish your article?
Everyone.
before we start.
I just want to apologize
about what happened last night.
I won't blame the alcohol.
That was all me.
It won't happen again.
Oh?
Why is Zy still here
after what happened last night?
Juancho already apologized to me.
And I need to finish my research.
[Aiah] Zy. are you sure?
Because I mean. if I were you--
[Juancho] Aiah.
I'm really sorry.
From here on out.
we'll remain professional.
Promise.
Okay. I forgive you.
All right. everybody.
let's talk about the bar menu.
We have tinuktok bites. celosia chips.
and laing quesadilla.
Okay. So. I guess we're good on the chows.
What about the drinks?
We have five signature drinks.
Okay. perfect!
I already got a bartender for tomorrow.
Jon. you're on cocktails.
Epi. staff walkthrough.
La. as usual. take care of the pantry.
-Aiah.
-[Aiah] Yes?
So far. so good.
I'm meeting
the two other investors later today.
The other one just arrived here in Naga.
I need you to meet with him today.
His name is Mr. JP.
-He's kinda quirky. but he's super rich.
-[phone vibrating]
[Juancho] Exactly what we need.
-[Aiah] Yes. exactly.
I need you to make sure to win him over.
Because we need him
for the investors' dinner.
-Okay?
-That's it. I got you.
Stop it. [disgust sound]
Zy. do you want to join?
I'm meeting an investor.
I just need to answer this.
[Matt on phone] I heard from your boss
that you changed your article.
[Zy] Yes.
I'm writing about Casa Rosa
and their expansion.
I asked for an extension
because I need more time to immerse.
Zy. just follow your boss. Okay?
He's not taking me seriously.
What do you expect?
-You didn't follow his directive.
-[scoffs]
Of course. you don't get it.
You're a managing editor.
You can do whatever you want to do.
and you can tell other people what to do.
Babe. don't ruin the trust
your editor is giving you.
David will get mad at you for sure.
Look. babe.
I'm just concerned about you.
That's all.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna take some time off from work
and go there to help you.
Anyway. I have to go.
I'm in between meetings.
-Bye.
-[call ends]
Are you okay?
Yeah.
[gentle music playing]
[van door slides open]
[bird chirping]
-[van door clicks shut]
-[music turns quirky]
[Juancho] What's he up to?
[Zy] Let's just do what he wants.
You need an investor. right?
[JP breathes deeply]
Hi. Sir JP. I'm Juancho.
Aiah's business partner.
And this is Zy.
My condolences. sir.
[quirky sting]
This is Froi. my partner.
You can give him a kiss.
He'd like that.
-[smooch]
-[quirky sting]
[Zy chuckles awkwardly]
[quirky sting]
Froi loves this place.
That's why
this is his death wish.
His wish is to…
[JP sobbing]
[JP laughing]
I'm sorry.
Froi doesn't want me to cry
while letting him go.
Can you please help me with that?
[JP] Froi and I met in high school.
He was my first boyfriend.
But we broke up after graduation.
Good thing the universe
brought us together again.
We met at a concert. of all places.
[JP sighs]
We were already working then.
The universe gave us a second chance.
Froi and I got back together.
That was the happiest day of my life.
But now…
he's gone.
I have to let him go.
Again.
Oh. no.
I feel like crying.
Oh my God. I think I'm gonna cry.
Help.
[singsongs]
Help me. I'm gonna cry.
It's okay.
[JP singsongs]
Breaths.
-Inhale.
-Good.
-Hold.
-[muffled sobs]
Exhale.
Nice one. Sir JP.
I'm still sad.
-[Zy] It's okay.
-[Juancho] Sir. just relax.
Here…
-I'm gonna cry!
-Do the thing!
What thing?
Do the thing! Juancho. do the thing!
That thing when you try to make me laugh.
Look at him! Look! Come on.
[muffled sobs]
[Zy whispers] Juancho. bigger!
With feelings!
Smile!
[laughs] Look!
[muffled scoffs]
Jump! Bigger dance!
It's not freaking like that.
It's like this.
-I'm doing it!
-Remember?
[Zy] The face!
Juancho. come on.
[Zy laughing] Juancho.
Do it.
Higher.
-[chuckles]
-[Zy and Juancho laughing]
[laughs]
[tender music playing]
-It still works!
-[both laughing]
You know.
it's really good
to surround yourself
with people who are in love.
-We have a new dance step.
-[Zy] That was good.
[Zy and Juancho laughing]
-[Zy] Did you see that?
-Hey.
The two of you.
promise me you'll stay in love!
Sorry. sir. Actually…
Yes. sir.
We promise we'll stay in love.
-Right. Juancho?
-Yes. sir.
Love is all around. Froi.
Even if you're gone.
love lives on.
[JP giggles]
Love lives on.
[tender music continues]
Come on. Let's just finish this.
[JP] Hey! Faster!
[Zy] Yes. sir!
[JP] I know you're here. my love.
This is your favorite view.
I'm fulfilling your wish.
Bye. Tweetney!
You're free now!
[shrieks] Bye!
[JP] After everything that
Froi and I have been through.
I realized that our love is like no other.
It's the kind of love that
you'll always be grateful for.
Smile!
[JP] And I'm grateful that
I experienced that love
-once in my life.
-[Juancho] Smile!
-One more!
-Okay!
-[Juancho] I'm coming!
-[JP] One more.
-[JP] Oh!
-[Zy squeals]
Smile!
Stop it!
Oh my! That's it.
[giggling]
[JP] You're both crazy.
Splash each other!
[JP] That's it. [laughs]
Your love is the most--
-It's too much.
-I agree.
One sec.
[Jon] Your love is the best.
Tin…
Here. [clears throat]
-Your love. Tin… Please.
-[Aiah] Oh. my God.
-Will you marry me?
-I really need to work.
[Aiah] Okay. one more time.
[Jon clears throat]
Tin. my baby.
will you marry me?
Are you proposing or reciting a poem?
Relax. okay? Take your time.
Look into her eyes
and think about
all of your memories together.
Of all the dishes that I've cooked
and tasted.
your lips.
your embrace.
your love is still the best.
It wasn't always happy
and easy.
We hurt each other.
But there's a reason why
we're still here together.
No matter the pain
and hardships.
I will always choose to love you
and be with you.
Will you marry me?
[soft music playing]
[Jon] Wow!
Boss! That was awesome!
I will use that!
-[Jon] I actually thought of that.
-[Juancho] Yeah?
[Juancho coughs]
[Jon] Boss.
I invited Tin
to the investors' dinner tomorrow.
Is it okay if I propose after?
As long as it's okay with Babi.
-Of course.
-Yes!
[Jon] Boss. one last request.
Please take the video.
Can I borrow this?
-Sure.
-[Jon] Nice!
Ma'am Zy.
will you help me with the bubbles?
That's Tin's favorite.
-For the vibe.
-[Zy chuckles] Sure.
-[Juancho] That's good.
-Babi. will Sir JP attend the dinner?
Yes. He'll come.
[cries. shrieks] Yes! Oh my God!
[Aiah] Thank you. Lord!
-Oh my God! Thank you. Zy!
-Thank you.
Oh my God. Perfect!
Our guest list is complete!
Oh my God! I could kiss you!
I dare you.
Just kidding!
See you. guys.
-[Juancho] See you!
-[Jon] See ya!
Thank you. Ma'am Zy.
Thank you. Bye!
[Zy on video] It's our soft opening today.
Ba. check the frame.
[Zy] You still have our old videos?
[chuckles]
What videos?
Those are private.
[chuckles]
-Stop that.
-Wait. Next.
-Look at this.
-What?
You were so clingy then.
[Zy on video] So. Ba…
[Juancho] Yes?
This will be your station.
[Juancho] Okay. Where's yours?
There.
-What?
-Yes.
No.
You should always be beside me.
No. Ba.
You have to focus.
You have to make sure the food is good.
Then. stay beside me.
-Like this.
-Okay. fine.
-We should always be this close.
-You're so clingy.
Okay. fine.
[chuckles]
Oh my God.
You're right. I was clingy.
-Give me that.
-Wait!
-Enough.
-Wait! Hold on!
[camera clicks]
[indistinct video playing]
Do you remember this?
Yeah.
[Zy on video] It's our soft opening today.
-[soft music playing]
-[indistinct dialogue]
[Zy] Ba. check this out!
Yoo-hoo!
Ba. check the sign.
What if nobody buys?
[Zy] Of course. not.
Our sign looks good.
Our food is so good.
And most of all.
the chef is so good-looking.
Ba. come on.
[Zy on video] Show me that smile.
-[woman] Hello. Do you have bottled water?
-[Juancho] Yes?
We do. Are you buying?
-[woman] Yes. One bottle.
-[Zy] One?
Miss. you're our first customer.
-[woman] Really?
-[Zy] Yes!
-Ba. our very first customer!
-Customer. customer!
[bell ringing]
-[Zy] Ba. go ahead.
-[chuckles]
[Juancho]
Here's your Bicol Express Burrito.
and since you're our first customer.
-you get a free kinalas nachos.
-Wow!
[Zy on video] Ba. why so serious?
[teases] Smile for me.
Show me that smile.
-Success.
-[Juancho] Thank you.
[Zy squeals]
[Zy] More!
[smooches]
[sweeping music playing]
[music fades]
[phone vibrating]
[Zy] Wait. you're already here?
-At the airport?
-[Matt] Yup. I just left the airport.
I'm on my way to the hotel already.
Okay. babe.
I'll see you at the hotel.
Let's grab some lunch.
Okay.
Okay. See you. babe. I love you.
Yeah.
See you.
Bye.
[poignant music playing]
Zy.
I'm sorry…
I have to go.
-[poignant music continues]
-[indistinct chatter]
[Lala] Boss. is this Sir JP's seat?
Where should we seat
the last-minute guests?
[Lala] Boss?
ZY. CAN WE TALK?
[Aiah] Juancho. we have one more hour
before dinner service.
I need you to focus. okay?
You need to be on top of everything.
We don't have room for mistakes tonight.
La?
[line ringing]
-Bro.
-[busy tone]
[Epi] The guests…
The guests are almost here.
Let's do the staff walkthrough.
Bro!
-[inhales sharply]
-[keypad typing]
Juancho. listen to me.
Just hear me out. okay?
I've known you for so long.
I know what you're planning to do.
But please. not now.
We're all depending on you-- Hey.
Don't leave us. Chef.
[car approaching]
-I have to go.
-Juancho--
[man] Okay. sir.
[Matt] Okay.
-[Matt] Okay.
-[paper rustles]
Yup. I think this is paid for.
Zy. can we talk?
Juancho. not now.
Not now? We need to talk.
[Zy] Juancho. not now!
-Bro. wait.
-[Juancho] Zy…
She doesn't want to talk to you.
So. please back off.
Matt. I just need to talk to Zy. Zy--
Bro. didn't you hear me?
-Don't push me!
-What the hell!
Juancho. enough!
Enough!
Matt. let's go.
Zy. please. I'm sorry.
What happened last night.
it meant something to me.
[melancholic music playing]
What happened last night?
[Juancho] Zy.
I know you feel the same way.
What is he talking about?
-Let's talk.
-Zy. please.
-Juancho--
-Talk to me!
Let's face this.
Let's fight for us!
Zy. please say something.
Please answer me.
Did you cheat on me?
-Zy.
-Matt.
Zy!
[Zy] Matt.
Matt!
[engine starts]
[engine revs]
Zy.
Zy. please.
Juancho. this is wrong.
Zy. I still love you.
And I know that you love me. too.
Juancho. my life is a mess right now.
I'll help you fix it.
What do you need?
Do you need to go back to New York?
I'll go with you.
But if it's messy there.
then maybe we can stay here?
Wherever you want.
In Manila?
Here in Bicol?
I'll find a way. Zy.
You will give up everything for me?
Zy. I'll do everything for us.
I just want to build a life with you.
[melancholic music playing]
[Zy inhales. exhales sharply]
Don't you want to be with me?
Don't you love me anymore?
I love you.
But that's not enough to fix my life.
I tried fixing your life before.
I know that you will do the same for me
because you love me.
But you'll get tired.
You'll be spent.
You can't fix my life for me
and then you ruin yours.
So. please.
Juancho. you have to let me go.
That's hard.
I love you so much.
I don't know how to let you go.
[melancholic music continues]
[Juancho sniffles]
[sniffles]
[breathes deeply. sniffles]
[melancholic music continues]
[Juancho] Sir JP!
The show is over. Juancho.
You missed your biggest break.
I'm sorry. sir.
No. I'm sorry.
I don't know if I can invest
in a restaurant
whose owner is not fully committed.
[van door slides open]
-[Jon] Boss. where were you?
-[engine starts]
[van driving off]
I wasn't able to propose to Tin.
[Epi] Let's go!
Bro.
[car door closes]
Is everything there?
[Aiah] The investors
were all looking for you.
I'm sorry. Aiah.
You should be sorry.
Aiah. I'll fix this.
No. Don't.
You know how much
this investment means to me.
But I came here and I stayed
because I wanted to support you.
Because we're partners. right?
But you left me hanging. Juancho.
[exhales deeply] You know what?
Maybe you're not cut out for this.
Because you're so fucking selfish.
-[sobbing]
-[melancholic music continues]
[curtain slides open]
[sighs]
Matt.
[Matt sighs]
Matt. I'm really sorry.
I'm sorry I hurt you.
You don't deserve it.
[Matt inhales. exhales deeply]
-[footsteps receding]
-[luggage rolling]
[door clicks open. shuts]
[Jun] Juancho!
Juancho!
Get up!
You need to open the restaurant.
I'm sorry. Papa Jun. Sorry.
[Juancho] I'll be quick.
Thank you.
Are you awake now?
Yes.
Your grandma used to scold me
because she couldn't entrust
the restaurant to me.
One night.
your father came home
with a young boy.
He was two years old.
He introduced you to us.
And then he left you with us.
Your Grandma Rosa and I took care of you.
Not long after. your Grandma Rosa died.
I was left alone.
Your father left me. too.
That's when I decided
that I will dedicate my life to Casa Rosa
together with you.
[gentle music playing]
I saw that you had a flair
for cooking growing up.
You're great.
You're creative.
You create a lot of original dishes.
You're happy in the kitchen.
The thing is.
you're too passionate.
When you love. it's intense.
You really love Zy. don't you?
You love her so much.
even if you know she's not for you.
you still run after her.
[Juancho sniffles]
Juancho.
you don't want to be abandoned.
but…
you abandon yourself
to chase somebody else.
[sniffles]
Sorry. Papa Jun.
[sobs. sniffles]
-[Jun sighs]
-[Juancho sniffles]
[Jun grunts]
My son.
wake up.
You can get through this.
[gentle music continues]
[door slides open]
-[sizzling]
-[uplifting music playing]
[simmering]
[indistinct dialogue]
-Why are we here?
-[Aiah] Let's go.
You'll apologize and say.
"Let's be professional."
I've heard that before.
Yes. La.
I want to apologize to all of you.
And yes.
I will be professional from now on.
But aside from that.
since I was inspired by all of you.
I want to present the new
and improved menu of Casa Rosa.
Here is "Cocido ala Padi".
It's as sour as the face you make
when I make stupid decisions.
But despite my shortcomings.
your love for me is as warm as the soup.
He's just guilty.
[Juancho] This is for you. Lala.
"Coco Leafy Lala".
You give strength
to all of us here in Casa Rosa.
[chortles]
I'm touched.
And. of course.
"Bicol Expressway to Babi's Heart".
With the right amount of spiciness
to kick me back to the right direction.
Aiah.
I want to be the best partner
that you deserve.
[indistinct chattering]
The newest addition to the menu.
"Jon's Fabulous Fritters".
I'm sorry.
I left you last night.
Let's push through with your proposal.
I'll help you.
I got you.
And lastly…
[Epi] He changed it.
…the reason why Casa Rosa is successful.
"Tinuktok Junior".
[heartwarming music playing]
Papa Jun.
thank you.
I don't know where I'll be without you.
Thank you for…
for being a father to me.
And I'm sorry
for all my shortcomings.
-[claps]
-Let's eat! [sniffles]
I'm really sorry.
[Epi] It's all good. We're good.
-Time to eat.
-[Lala] All good now.
-[Juancho] Let's eat.
-Boss. how long did you rehearse that?
-[laughter]
-[Juancho] Hey.
-[Lala] Did you stay up all night?
-[Epi] Let's eat. boss.
-[Juancho] La?
-[Jon] Flowers.
[Jon] Balloons.
-[Juancho] Balloons?
-[Epi] Not sure.
Jon!
Hey.
Relax.
[exhales sharply]
-Thanks. boss.
-Okay?
[Juancho chuckles]
Shit!
The bubbles!
[Jon] Okay.
Never mind. I got this!
Boss.
[heartwarming music continues]
[giggles]
Welcome back. 2022 Chili Queen!
Hey.
-[laughs]
-Chili Queen!
[Lala] Enjoy!
Papa Jun!
[Zy] You're so pretty!
[shrieks]
You're so pretty. Tin!
[laughter]
-[Zy] Here!
-[Jon] It's the wind.
[laughter]
-[Jon] My Chili Queen.
-[Lala] Ma'am Aiah!
Tin. our journey was not easy.
We were apart
for most of our relationship.
but we never gave up.
You never gave up on me.
despite all my shortcomings.
You are the right person for me.
Of all the dishes
that I've cooked and tasted.
your love
is the most delicious.
[Tin] Really?
Promise?
-[Jon] I promise!
-You swear?
-I'm not laing.
-[chuckles]
[Jon] But Tin.
no matter how hard it is.
I will always choose you.
And so…
Tin.
my baby. [chuckles]
Will you be my casa?
-Of course.
-Really?
Yes! [giggles]
[people cheering]
[cheering continues]
[Tin] Does it fit?
[Jon chuckles]
-[Jon] It fits.
-[Tin giggles]
-[Tin] Oh. you.
-[Jon] My baby. I love you!
-[people cheering]
-[Jon] Yes!
[cheering continues]
[Juancho] Hey. come here. Jon!
[music fades]
Where are you going now?
To the airport.
I need to go back to New York
to figure out what I really want to do.
You'll figure it out.
What about you?
Me?
I'll focus on the Manila branch.
I'm rooting for you.
Thank you for stopping by. Zy.
Thank you for accepting me.
["Paubaya" by Moira Dela Torre playing]
Nope.
[low-pitched voice] Nope.
[Zy grunts]
Thank you for the ride.
I hope you miss your flight.
-[phone vibrating]
-[grunts]
[Zy] Lei. I'm already here at the airport.
See you inside.
[Lei on phone] See you. sis.
[Juancho exhales deeply]
So.
are you sure you didn't leave anything?
I'm sure.
Thank you for the ride.
-Your hair's a little messy.
-[chuckles]
-Sorry.
-Thank you.
Go ahead.
You might miss your flight.
[Juancho] Zy!
[Zy] What?
Nice meeting you!
You too!
[chuckles]
[Juancho] Zy!
Zy!
I'll follow you in Manila!
[mouthing] What?
I'll go to Manila!
[whispers] It's your choice.
Bye.
Zy!
Juancho.
I'm happy for you.
["Paubaya" by Moira Dela Torre playing]
[song fades]